foreign
[Music]
all right Fernanda says what is the
ideal LDL
ideal LDL depends on whether or not you
have been diagnosed with heart disease
if you have not a lifetime LDL well
actually a lifetime LDL under 100.
um uh uh should protect you from heart
disease however if you didn't figure
this out into middle age and you're uh
in your ldl's uh uh too high and you're
trying to get it down to prevent heart
disease then 70 would be the target if
you already have heart disease
um uh then the target uh draw in terms
of secondary prevention to prevent the
second heart attack drops down to like
30 to 50 or basically as low as possible
so wait a second could there be a harm
of having cholesterol too low we didn't
know until pcsk 9 Inhibitors came out we
have these new biologic injectable drugs
which can drop people's cholesterol LDL
cholesterol into the single digits and
um
still not seeing any problems with a
hormone manufacture like testosterone
estrogen or
any other issues that have piled on uh
so only benefit as you go lower lower
but we don't uh most people should not
need drugs to get their LDL down they
just need to cut out or cut down on the
three things that increase one's
cholesterol and that is saturated fat
found mostly in animal fats and junk
trans fats found almost exclusively now
in animal fat now that's been removed
from the food supply
um from a partial hydroxine into oils
and third is dietary cluster I found
predominantly an X but throughout the
animal kingdom just do all that your
cholesterol should drop right down add
in a whole bunch of high fiber plant
foods which is say whole plant Foods
um and you can push your cholesterol
down even further
um I have an LP little a
um video up trying to think if I have
another one coming up
um I was just looking at that for the
book
um
uh but uh but I go through exactly where
we should uh have a Target up a little
late and what we can do about it
um uh yes in addition to eating healthy
there are a few Foods particularly that
may lower LP little a further I think
those are
um black cumin seed and um flax seeds
but check the video to find out okay
Jesse has natural low um HDL with a
hover plant-based diet LDL triglycerides
plummeted fantastic but
um that talks about a triglyceridatio
ratio what's important uh a number to
track LDL is an important number to
track we used to think HDL so-called
good cholesterol was good and actually
had benefits in terms of reducing
disease risk it turns out that is not
the case uh based on a whole range of
evidence
um including drugs that um that raise
HDL which actually had to be stopped
earlier because it was killing people
and probably most importantly these
so-called mendelian randomization
studies where people who just
genetically at Birth born with genes
that give them kind of unnaturally
elevated SEO throughout their entire
lives regardless what they eat or how
they live
um do not actually have lower
cardiovascular disease however
those born with high LDL die early
because from cardiovascular disease and
those were low LDL are protected from
heart disease regardless of what they
eat proving that
effectively proven of course we can
actually there's actually real proven
proving in terms of randomized
controlled trials but um it's the best
um in terms you get for observational
data
um which um so the LDL is actually a um
a risk factor not just a correlate so
for example you know I do a video
talking about H this HDL things one of
my egg videos
where
um something like you know having lots
of uh what a gene uh what was it tennis
shoes in your house associated with
Better Health
um but uh but that's not because gym
shoes actually help your health directly
it's just a proxy for
um something like exercise which
actually does help you out so you know
those people that
um who carry around cigarette lighters
probably live short in lives but not
because of Cameron cigarette lighters
it's not a uh a cause and effect a
causal risk factor
um it's uh um and similarly HDL is not a
causal
um protective factor for heart disease
so don't worry about your HDL worry
about your LDL and it's wonderful that
they're down and uh that's fantastic
congratulations
okay Francis says what is mainstream
what is the main reason why one is A1C
fluctuates from high to low and high to
low that is well a oh B12 supplement
help with diabetic neuropathy okay for
those of you who are like what is an A1c
um it is a measure of kind of long-term
blood sugar control over the last few
months or so
um but really uh biased towards kind of
more recent events and so the main
reason is people are eating different
foods and um although women can get
hormonal changes throughout the month
um that even if they're eating the same
thing they can have different blood
sugar responses so that could be one
reason
um and uh you know if you're sick uh you
know you have really high blood
pressures
um uh even if you're kind of eating
healthy but typically
um we tend to think of HBA A1C as
um in terms of diabetic control and how
well medications are working
um and for pre-diabetes or uh in general
um it's uh typically uh um what's
happening with a diet uh primarily the
glycemic load of different foods and so
I encourage people to cut out uh refined
grains
um and things that cause too high of a
blood sugar Spike
okay santanu says the fan base diet
reduced sugar substantially I want to
know how do I reduce insulin resistance
great current fasting insulin is um 16
looking to reduce it uh HDL has gone
down we don't worry about HCL it's not a
cause of risk factor for heart disease
but if you want to reduce your insulin
resistance
um you decrease the quality of insulin
resistance which is excess saturated fat
intake in the context of a hyper caloric
diet
um or excess visceral adiposity if you
um if your waste uh measure your belly
button is more than half your height you
need to lose weight to reduce that
visceral fat and decrease insulin
resistance regardless of what you eat
okay BLK says type 2 diabetic oh but
eating healthy wonderful not on meds
fantastic oh but can't get glucose under
control
um and so uh one of the reasons maybe
you're still uh you're suffering insulin
resistance from excess visceral fat
um so if you have excess abdominal fat
um I can spill fat in your bloodstream
and so even if you don't have
um it going into your mouth you still
have these high levels of fat in your
blood and that um interferes with um
insulin responsiveness in your muscles
and liver
um and that's what causes
um type 2 diabetes especially when it
offloads fat to your poor pancreas and
can destroy some of your insulin
producing cells
um and so weight loss would be the next
step and if your glucose is not under
control you should
um indeed
um I talked to your doctors about being
on meds until
um something like metformin until uh you
can get it under control with dye it
though it may take weight loss to
drop your visceral fat to levels
um uh that you're uh where uh your
insulin resistance drops enough that you
can reverse your diabetes
[Music]
foreign